{
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "What is the maximum number of members in the town committees?",
            "options": [
                "a) 20",
                "b) 10",
                "c) 7",
                "d) 15"
            ],
            "answer": "a) 20"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the maximum number of members present in a municipality?",
            "options": [
                "a) 30",
                "b) 20",
                "c) 60",
                "d) 15"
            ],
            "answer": "a) 30"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Guwahati Municipal Corporation established?",
            "options": [
                "a) 1969",
                "b) 1974",
                "c) 1975",
                "d) 1984"
            ],
            "answer": "b) 1974"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which part of the Indian Constitution mentions the panchayat system?",
            "options": [
                "a) 9th [Part IX]",
                "b) 10th",
                "c) 9th (a) Part",
                "d) 8th part"
            ],
            "answer": "a) 9th [Part IX]"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which part of the Indian Constitution mentions about municipality?",
            "options": [
                "a) 9th",
                "b) 10th part",
                "c) 9th (A) part [Part IX A]",
                "d) 8th part"
            ],
            "answer": "c) 9th (A) part [Part IX A]"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Article refers to panchayat system in the Part IX of the Constitution?",
            "options": [
                "a) 243",
                "b) 243 (Q)",
                "c) 244",
                "d) 242"
            ],
            "answer": "b) 243 (Q)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Article refers to the urban area in [Part IX(A)] section of the Constitution?",
            "options": [
                "a) 243",
                "b) 243 (Q)",
                "c) 244",
                "d) 242"
            ],
            "answer": "a) 243"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the chief of the municipality?",
            "options": [
                "a) Mayor",
                "b) Representative of the constituency",
                "c) Deputy Commissioner",
                "d) Councillor"
            ],
            "answer": "a) Mayor"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the political representative of the municipal corporation?",
            "options": [
                "a) Councillor",
                "b) Corporation Secretary",
                "c) Deputy Commissioner",
                "d) Urban"
            ],
            "answer": "a) Councillor"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the total land area of Bodoland region?",
            "options": [
                "a) 10,200 sq km",
                "b) 8,970 sq km",
                "c) 9,612 sq km",
                "d) 11,002 sq km"
            ],
            "answer": "a) 10,200 sq km"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many constituency seats are there in Bodoland region?",
            "options": [
                "a) 40",
                "b) 46",
                "c) 60",
                "d) 50"
            ],
            "answer": "a) 40"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many districts have autonomy under the Sixth Schedule?",
            "options": [
                "a) Two",
                "b) Three",
                "c) Four",
                "d) Five"
            ],
            "answer": "b) Three"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Mishing Autonomous Council formed?",
            "options": [
                "a) 1994",
                "b) 1995",
                "c) 1993",
                "d) 1996"
            ],
            "answer": "c) 1993"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was Rabha Hasong Autonomous Council formed?",
            "options": [
                "a) 1995",
                "b) 2013",
                "c) 2015",
                "d) 2003"
            ],
            "answer": "a) 1995"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Sonowal Kachari Autonomous Council formed?",
            "options": [
                "a) 2005",
                "b) 2015",
                "c) 2014",
                "d) 1995"
            ],
            "answer": "a) 2005"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Tiwa Autonomous Councils formed?",
            "options": [
                "a) 2005",
                "b) 2015",
                "c) 2010",
                "d) 2019"
            ],
            "answer": "c) 2010"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the total number of seats in the Tiwa Autonomous Council?",
            "options": [
                "a) 36",
                "b) 26",
                "c) 40",
                "d) 29"
            ],
            "answer": "a) 36"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Assam police department formed?",
            "options": [
                "a) 1926",
                "b) 1947",
                "c) 1826",
                "d) 1939"
            ],
            "answer": "a) 1826"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of Jyoti Prasad Agarwalaâ€™s wife?",
            "options": [
                "a) Lavita Baruah",
                "b) Debajani Bhuyan",
                "c) Malati Baruah",
                "d) Reena Agarwal"
            ],
            "answer": "c) Malati Baruah"
        },
        {
            "question": "Guwahati city has been divided into how many police commissioner districts?",
            "options": [
                "a) Three",
                "b) Four",
                "c) Five",
                "d) Two"
            ],
            "answer": "d) Two"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Assam Public Service Commission constituted?",
            "options": [
                "a) 1935",
                "b) 1936",
                "c) 1937",
                "d) 1938"
            ],
            "answer": "a) 1935"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first Chairman of Assam Public Service Commission?",
            "options": [
                "a) James Hezelett",
                "b) E. P. Bark",
                "c) A. J. Das",
                "d) Kamleswar Das"
            ],
            "answer": "a) James Hezelett"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first chairman of Assam Public Service Commission of postindependence Assam?",
            "options": [
                "a) H.C. Bhuyan",
                "b) A. N. Bhattacharya",
                "c) Kameshwar Das",
                "d) Kocantaly"
            ],
            "answer": "c) Kameshwar Das"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who appoints the Chairman of the Assam Public Service Commission?",
            "options": [
                "a) Governor",
                "b) Prime Minister",
                "c) Chief Minister.",
                "d) Home Minister"
            ],
            "answer": "a) Governor"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the tenure of Chairman of Assam Public Service Commission?",
            "options": [
                "a) Five years.",
                "b) Four years",
                "c) Six years",
                "d) Eight years"
            ],
            "answer": "c) Six years"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Assam State Finance Commission constituted?",
            "options": [
                "a) 23 June 1995",
                "b) 18 April 2001",
                "c) 6 February 2006",
                "d) 23 April 2010"
            ],
            "answer": "c) 6 February 2006"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Assam State Election Commission constituted?",
            "options": [
                "a) 1993",
                "b) 1951",
                "c) 1994",
                "d) 1972"
            ],
            "answer": "c) 1994"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the first tea garden of Assam established?",
            "options": [
                "a) 1839",
                "b) 1838",
                "c) 1837",
                "d) 1840"
            ],
            "answer": "b) 1838"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where was the first tea garden to be set up in Assam?",
            "options": [
                "a) Jorhat",
                "b) Vishwanath",
                "c) Margherita",
                "d) Chabua"
            ],
            "answer": "a) Jorhat"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the largest tea garden in Assam?",
            "options": [
                "a) Manobari Tea Garden",
                "b) Gagharajan Tea Garden",
                "c) Deepling Tea Garden",
                "d) Galleky Tea Garden"
            ],
            "answer": "b) Gagharajan Tea Garden"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Toklai Tea Research Centre established in Jorhat?",
            "options": [
                "a) 1910",
                "b) 1974",
                "c) 1911",
                "d) 1970"
            ],
            "answer": "c) 1911"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the real name of Manoni Roisom Goswami?",
            "options": [
                "a) Indira Goswami",
                "b) Indira Miri",
                "c) Bina Baideu",
                "d) Sulekha Devi"
            ],
            "answer": "a) Indira Goswami"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Tea Auction Centre established in Guwahati?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1974",
                "B. 1970",
                "C. 2017",
                "D. 2001"
            ],
            "answer": "B. 1970"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which oil refinery in Assam is known as 'Assam Accord Refinery'?",
            "options": [
                "A. Digboi Refinery",
                "B. Noonmati refinery",
                "C. Bongaigaon Refinery",
                "D. Numalighar Refinery"
            ],
            "answer": "C. Bongaigaon Refinery"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many oil refineries are there in Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. Four",
                "B. Five",
                "C. Three",
                "D. Six"
            ],
            "answer": "B. Five"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the first sugarcane industry of Assam established in Barua bamun Gaon village in Golaghat?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1958",
                "B. 1971",
                "C. 1955",
                "D. 1956"
            ],
            "answer": "C. 1955"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year Mamoni Roisom Goswami received Sahitya Akademi Award?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1981",
                "B. 1983",
                "C. 1982",
                "D. 1984"
            ],
            "answer": "C. 1982"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was Assam's first plywood industry â€˜Assam Saw Mill and Timberâ€™ established?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1925",
                "B. 1942",
                "C. 1920",
                "D. 1943"
            ],
            "answer": "A. 1925"
        },
        {
            "question": "What industries did the English company Ward and Company set up in Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. Fertilizer industry",
                "B. Sugar industry",
                "C. Acid industry",
                "D. Plywood Industry"
            ],
            "answer": "B. Sugar industry"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the first paper mill established in Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1970",
                "B. 1985",
                "C. 1971",
                "D. 1961"
            ],
            "answer": "A. 1970"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the paper mill in Jogighopa, Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. Hindustan Paper Corporation",
                "B. Nagaon paper Mill (1970)",
                "C. Ashok Paper Mills Limited",
                "D. None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "C. Ashok Paper Mills Limited"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Assam tourism policy been adopted?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1995",
                "B. 2014",
                "C. 2008",
                "D. 2001"
            ],
            "answer": "B. 2014"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which national park in Assam has the highest number of inflow of tourists?",
            "options": [
                "A. Manas national Park",
                "B. Orang National Park",
                "C. Kaziranga National Park",
                "D. Nameri National Park"
            ],
            "answer": "C. Kaziranga National Park"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is known as the 'Golden Silk' of Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. Jute cloth",
                "B. Eri cloth",
                "C. Muga cloth",
                "D. Cotton cloth"
            ],
            "answer": "C. Muga cloth"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the first five-year plan launched in Assam?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1950",
                "B. 1951",
                "C. 1956",
                "D. 1949"
            ],
            "answer": "B. 1951"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was NITI Aayog constituted?",
            "options": [
                "A. 2016",
                "B. 2015",
                "C. 2014",
                "D. 2010"
            ],
            "answer": "C. 2014"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Irrigation Department of Assam established?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1974",
                "B. 1980",
                "C. 1951",
                "D. 1971"
            ],
            "answer": "C. 1951"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was Assam State Electricity Board formed?",
            "options": [
                "A. 1950",
                "B. 1975",
                "C. 1958",
                "D. 1956"
            ],
            "answer": "B. 1975"
        },
        {
            "question": "The second film of Jyoti Prasad Agarewal was?",
            "options": [
                "A. Joymati",
                "B. Lavita",
                "C. Sonitkuwori",
                "D. Indramalati"
            ],
            "answer": "A. Joymati"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was Assam Power Distribution Company Limited (APDCL) formed?",
            "options": [
                "A. 23 October, 2009",
                "B. 1 June, 2005",
                "C. 10 May 2005",
                "D. 5 May 2009"
            ],
            "answer": "A. 23 October, 2009"
        }
    ]
}
